Jefforson Ewing Peter

Chennai, TN, India jefforsonewing@outlook.com

(+91) 9788 899 869

Category Account Manager

An MBA graduate with 8 years of experience in the E-commerce/sales industry.

Extremely organized with the ability to work both independently or as part of a team, demonstrating the motivation and multi-tasking abilities required to meet demanding deadlines while maintaining the high standards.

A professional with excellent interpersonal skills and can communicate concisely at all levels. Currently looking for a new and challenging position where I can develop my knowledge and experience.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Category Account Manager

Clues Network Pvt Ltd (Shop clues)

Mar 2021 - Present

- (Indian Online market place)
- Helped existing sellers in increasing their online sales by x3 times.
- Consistently achieved and over achieved the required target and always positioned amongst the top3 achievers.
- Onboarding of merchants/ manufactures (both national and International) who have been doing business
 offline. Helped them increase in sales by 25%, by selling their product directly to customers avoiding offline
 middlemen with competitive price points.

Sales Manager Whitehat Jr. Pvt. Ltd. Oct 2020 - Feb 2021

(Seller of computer coding classes for kids and students)

- Conversion of leads to business by 75%.
- Persuaded International customers (US and Canada) and selling our product. Achieved 100% sales target.
- Faster closure of domestic and commercial deals.

Area Supply Manager

OYO Hotels & Homes Pvt. Ltd.

Apr 2019 - Sep 2020

(Indian multinational homes and living spaces)

- Acquiring and converting individual houses (3bhk & above) to sophisticated BnB.
- Successfully converted 80% of the acquired property from rental model to revenue share model
- Achieved 100% of monthly target. Kept my no.1 spot for 4 months and on top 3 month on month.
- Enrolling celebrities' properties.

City Supply Manager

CASA2Stays Pvt Ltd (Fab Hotels)

Jun 2018 - Feb 2019

(Chain of budget friendly hotels - Hospitality services)

- Responsible for Cross-functional co-ordination with multiple teams (Operations, Sales, Accounts, Customer Service, OTA Cluster, On-boarding) in inter and Intra geographies
- Acquiring of hotels on revenue sharing basis and making it as best in class budget friendly hotels.
- Explored and Identified new locations and acquired the first properties for FabHotels.

Education Specialist

XSeed Education Pvt.Ltd.

Sep 2017 - Jun 2018

(Global K-8 learning company)

- Brought in 50 lacs INR business by selling the XSeed product in schools in 3 months.
- Onboarded the largest school in Kanyakumari to use Xseed learning product

Key Account Manager

One97 Communications Ltd (Paytm Mall)

Sep 2015 - Aug 2017

(E-commerce/ Payments Bank)

- Helped existing sellers in increasing their online sales by x3 times.
- Onboarding of merchants/ manufactures and helped them increase their sales by 20% by making them participate in promotions & Deals.
- Enrolled major retail market players in payments bank by increasing business by x2.

Field Officer Sales

Quikr.com

Jun 2014 - Sep 2015

(Online market place and classifieds)

- Selling of online space for advertisement for retailers and brands.
- Closed a deal for 1.5 lacs INR in single sitting.

EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Master of Business Administration, Vellore Institute of Technology. GPA: 6.57/10.00 *Jul 2012 – Apr 2014*Modules included: , Brand management, Retailing, E-commerce, promotion management.

Main project: A study on competitors of TANCEM.

Bachelor of Commerce, Madurai Kamaraj University. GPA: 7.53/10.00. Modules included: Business communication, commercial law, Salesmanship

Jun 2009 – Apr 2012

Software skills:

- Microsoft office
- Sales Force

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above given information is true and to the best of my knowledge

Jefforson Ewing Peter